♪The wind blows, but I don't see you♪
♪ تهب الرياح، ولكنني لا أراك ♪
♪I added a few more strokes♪
♪ أضفت بعض الضربات الإضافية ♪
♪To the ending♪
♪ إلى النهاية ♪
♪With the flowers falling and the time passing♪
♪ مع تساقط الزهور ومرور الوقت ♪
♪Leaving only memories behind♪
♪ لا تترك سوى الذكريات خلفك ♪
♪The wind blows from a long distance♪
♪ تهب الرياح من مسافة طويلة ♪
♪Yet, you didn't show up♪
♪ ومع ذلك، لم تحضر ♪
♪This love is full of regrets♪
♪ هذا الحب مليء بالندم ♪
♪You are but a dream in this fleeting life♪
♪أنت مجرد حلم في هذه الحياة العابرة♪
[Part For Ever]
[الجزء إلى الأبد]
[Adapted from the novel by Jing Mo,]
[مقتبس من رواية جينغ مو،]
[My Lord, Madam Doesn't Want to See You Again]
[ربي، سيدتي لا تريد رؤيتك مرة أخرى]
[Episode 20]
[الحلقة 20]
[Goodness And Virtue Bring Fragrance] First bow to the heaven and earth.
[الخير والفضيلة تفوح عطرًا] انحنِ أولاً إلى السماء والأرض.
Second bow to your parents,
الانحناءة الثانية لوالديك،
Then bow to each other.
ثم انحنوا لبعضكم البعض.
Our destinies don't align,
مصائرنا لا تتوافق
♪Playing the Guqin under the moon, recalling his poem♪
♪ العزف على Guqin تحت القمر، مستذكرًا قصيدته ♪
our hearts diverge,
قلوبنا تتباعد
and our paths diverge.
وتتباعد مساراتنا.
♪Years have passed, the flowers have bloomed again♪
♪ مرت السنوات، وأزهرت الزهور من جديد ♪
♪In this life without you, day and night feel endless♪
♪ في هذه الحياة بدونك، يبدو الليل والنهار بلا نهاية ♪
♪In this old dreamland, memories of past lives are locked away♪
♪ في أرض الأحلام القديمة هذه، يتم حبس ذكريات الحياة الماضية بعيدًا ♪
♪I didn't see you when I woke up and opened the windows♪
♪ لم أراك عندما استيقظت وفتحت النوافذ ♪
Thus,
هكذا،
let's part ways amicably,
دعونا نفترق الطرق وديًا،
each finding our own happiness.
كل يجد سعادتنا الخاصة.
[Divorce Letter]
[رسالة الطلاق]
♪We didn't know or understand each other♪
♪ لم نعرف أو نفهم بعضنا البعض ♪
♪Unbothered by worldly affairs♪
♪ غير منزعج من شؤون الدنيا ♪
♪All perils stop on my brow as I await your return♪
♪ كل المخاطر تتوقف على جبيني بينما أنتظر عودتك ♪
Sister,
أخت،
oh, I should say,
أوه، ينبغي أن أقول،
little sister.
اختي الصغيرة.
As the wife, I haven't even taken my seat,
كزوجة، لم أقم حتى بأخذ مقعدي،
yet you, a concubine, have already started dining.
ومع ذلك، أنت، محظية، قد بدأت بالفعل في تناول الطعام.
Isn't that against the rules?
أليس هذا ضد القواعد؟
What kind of attitude is this?
أي نوع من الموقف هذا؟
How dare you, a mere concubine,
كيف تجرؤين، مجرد محظية،
not respond to the wife's questions?
لا ترد على أسئلة الزوجة؟
This is for not following the rules!
هذا لعدم اتباع القواعد!
You...
أنت...
Maids!
الخادمات!
Teach this wretched woman a lesson!
لقن هذه المرأة البائسة درسا!
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Ling,
لينغ،
I merely lectured Wan'er a little.
لقد قمت فقط بإلقاء محاضرة على Wan'er قليلاً.
And she resorted to violence.
ولجأت إلى العنف.
My face is not disfigured, is it?
وجهي ليس مشوهاً، أليس كذلك؟
Hanfeng,
هانفينج،
take her back to her room.
إعادتها إلى غرفتها.
Yes, My Lord.
نعم سيدي.
Ling,
لينغ،
my face hurts.
وجهي يؤلمني.
♪I spread out paper and pen, writing a quatrain♪
♪ قمت بتوزيع الورقة والقلم، وأكتب رباعية ♪
♪I think of you again as I write down the past memories♪
♪ أفكر فيك مرة أخرى وأنا أكتب ذكريات الماضي ♪
♪Who did I share my emotions with during those years?♪
♪ مع من شاركت مشاعري خلال تلك السنوات؟ ♪
Ling, for the past ten years,
لينغ، على مدى السنوات العشر الماضية،
I've been fantasizing about marrying you.
لقد كنت أتخيل أن أتزوجك.
Now,
الآن،
the dream has finally come true.
الحلم أصبح حقيقة أخيرا.
Why don't you stay tonight?
لماذا لا تبقى الليلة؟
You know
أنت تعرف
why I went along with your act.
لماذا ذهبت مع الفعل الخاص بك.
Dreams really are easily shattered.
الأحلام حقا تتحطم بسهولة.
Sometimes I really wonder
في بعض الأحيان أتساءل حقا
what it is about Su Wan'er that you like.
ما الذي يعجبك في Su Wan'er.
Does one need a reason to like someone?
هل يحتاج المرء إلى سبب ليحب شخص ما؟
Just like I like you for your martial prowess,
مثلما أحبك لبراعتك القتالية،
extraordinary demeanor,
سلوك غير عادي,
and unparalleled greatness.
وعظمة لا مثيل لها.
I could go on listing reasons for three days and nights.
يمكنني الاستمرار في سرد ​​الأسباب لمدة ثلاثة أيام وليالٍ.
But my love for her
لكن حبي لها
doesn't require any reason.
لا يتطلب أي سبب.
You see,
هل ترى،
even your ruthlessness
وحتى قسوتك
is enough to captivate me.
يكفي أن يأسرني.
I never expected you
لم أتوقع منك أبدا
to like me this much.
أن تحبني بهذا القدر.
Of course.
بالطبع.
One of us is madly in love,
من منا يحب بجنون
and the other one is obsessively infatuated.
والآخر مفتون بالوسواس.
It's only right for us to be together.
من الصواب أن نكون معًا.
Ling...
لينغ...
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Are you all right?
هل انت بخير؟
It's the cold syndrome.
إنها متلازمة البرد.
I've been tormented by it for many years.
لقد تعذبت بسبب ذلك لسنوات عديدة.
You know that better than anyone.
أنت تعرف ذلك أفضل من أي شخص آخر.
I could die at any moment.
يمكن أن أموت في أي لحظة.
But it's not a full moon today.
لكنه ليس اكتمال القمر اليوم.
Why would it attack early?
لماذا يهاجم مبكرا؟
I'm hungry.
أنا جائع.
Go ask the kitchen to prepare food for me.
اذهب واطلب من المطبخ تحضير الطعام لي.
I...
أنا...
What's the matter?
ماذا جرى؟
Are you starving me because I'm a concubine?
هل تقوم بتجويعي لأنني محظية؟
I won't dare to.
لن أجرؤ على ذلك.
Are you trying to trick me into giving you the antidote?
هل تحاول خداعي لأعطيك الترياق؟
What do you take me for?
ماذا تأخذ مني؟
That's Wan'er's lifesaving medicine.
هذا هو دواء وانير المنقذ للحياة.
I'd rather die than take it.
أفضل أن أموت على أن أعتبره.
Even if you want to die, I won't let you.
حتى لو كنت تريد أن تموت، فلن أسمح لك بذلك.
You really are tricking me.
أنت حقا تخدعني.
My Lord.
ربي.
Take her away.
خذها بعيدا.
The effects of this Cold Powder
آثار هذا المسحوق البارد
really resemble the cold symptoms.
تشبه حقا أعراض البرد.
My Lord,
ربي،
this is the only antidote that can treat your cold symptoms.
هذا هو الترياق الوحيد الذي يمكنه علاج أعراض البرد.
If you give it to Her Ladyship,
إذا أعطيته للسيدة،
your life will be in danger.
حياتك ستكون في خطر.
Nothing is more important than her life.
لا يوجد شيء أكثر أهمية من حياتها.
Wan'er?
ماذا؟
[To Ling Xiao]
[إلى لينغ شياو]
[Divorce Letter]
[رسالة الطلاق]
♪People sit silently by candlelight as night begins♪
♪يجلس الناس بصمت على ضوء الشموع مع بداية الليل♪
♪A play of sorrows and joys, your role, my outline♪
♪ مسرحية أحزان وأفراح، دورك، مخططي ♪
♪Though the dream is over, the feelings are hard to let go♪
♪على الرغم من أن الحلم قد انتهى، إلا أنه من الصعب التخلي عن المشاعر
♪Everyone is filled with sorrow and pity♪
♪ الجميع مملوء بالحزن والشفقة ♪
♪Alas, the mortal world has too many spectators♪
♪ للأسف، العالم الفاني لديه الكثير من المتفرجين ♪
♪You turn back to ascend the stage wearing a green robe♪
♪ تعود للخلف لتصعد على المسرح مرتديًا رداء أخضر ♪
♪A song asking about heart matters, but who will answer?♪
♪ أغنية تسأل عن أمور القلب ولكن من يجيب؟ ♪
♪An old dream with infatuation and resentment and complications♪
♪ حلم قديم به افتتان وسخط وتعقيدات ♪
♪You sing for me♪
♪ أنت تغني لي ♪
♪In the play, telling of separations and reunions♪
♪ في المسرحية تحكي حالات الانفصال ولم الشمل ♪
♪Pear blossoms fall and flowing sleeves feel like yesterday♪
♪ تتساقط أزهار الكمثرى وتبدو الأكمام المتدفقة وكأنها بالأمس ♪
♪The heart is closed, unable to gaze at the emotional eyes♪
♪ القلب مغلق، غير قادر على التحديق في العيون العاطفية ♪
♪This life is filled with too much affection♪
♪ هذه الحياة مليئة بالكثير من المودة ♪
♪Amid the applause, who can see through it?♪
♪ وسط التصفيق، من يستطيع أن يرى من خلاله؟ ♪
♪Aren't the characters in the play you and me?♪
♪ أليست الشخصيات في المسرحية أنت وأنا؟ ♪